Preliminary Guide to the Wendell Willkie Presidential Campaign Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Wendell Lewis Willkie presidential campaign papers
1940-1940
MS 556
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
2.75
The papers consist of press releases, subject files, speeches, clippings, organization files and campaign ephemera from the presidential campaign conducted by Wendell Willkie in 1940.
Willkie, Wendell L. (Wendell Lewis), 1892-1944
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Accession received from Museum of Fine Arts, Houston, 6 October 1989.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Biographical / Historical
Wendell Willkie received his A.B. from Indiana University in 1913. He was admitted to the Indiana bar in 1916, and practiced law in Indiana and New York. In 1940, Willkie became a candidate for president of the United States.
Scope and Contents
The papers consist of press releases, subject files, speeches, clippings, organization files and campaign ephemera from the presidential campaign conducted by Wendell Willkie in 1940.
Campaign literature, 1940 -- Republican; United States -- Politics and government; Politicians; Willkie, Wendell L. (Wendell Lewis), 1892-1944; Republican Party (U.S.: 1854- )
- Inventory
  - ALS to Mrs. Robert Franklin Ives, 1940 April 18 (Box 1)
  - Press releases (Box 1)
    - 1940 Sep 13-Oct 22 (Box 1)
    - 1940 Oct 23-Nov 1 (Box 2)
  - Subject files
    - Agriculture (Box 2)
    - Bureaucracy (Box 2)
    - 18th Congressional district, New York (Box 2)
    - Finance (Box 2)
    - Foreign affairs (Box 2)
    - Foreign trade (Box 2)
    - Foreign trade (Box 3)
    - General economic conditions (Box 3)
    - Government and business (Box 3)
    - Hatch Act (Box 3)
    - Housing (Box 3)
    - Judiciary and court plan (Box 3)
    - Labor and N.L.R.B. (Box 3)
    - LaGuardia, Mayor Fiorello H. (Box 3)
    - Machines (Box 3)
    - Motion picture industry (Box 3)
    - National defense (Box 3)
    - National defense (Box 4)
    - Negroes (Box 4)
    - Roosevelt, President Franklin D. (Box 4)
    - Roosevelt, replies to (Box 4)
    - Social Security, Old Age Pension, Unemployment Insurance (Box 4)
    - Third term (Box 4)
    - Tolerance (Box 4)
    - Unemployment relief (Box 4)
    - Utilities (Box 4)
    - Votes (Box 4)
    - Wallace, Henry A. (Box 4)
    - W.P.A. (Box 4)
    - Youth (Box 4)
  - Speeches and excerpts (miscellaneous) (Box 5)
  - Clippings and leaflets (Box 5)
  - Associated Willkie Clubs of America: "We the People" Willkie campaign: mimeographed material (Box 5)
  - Manhattan Campaign Committee for Willkie and McNary: instructions to volunteers (Box 5)
  - Independent Speakers Bureau: schedule, speeches, miscellaneous papers (Box 5)
  - "Dead End Kid" speeches (Box 5)
  - Campaign buttons (Box 5)
  - Unprocessed papers (clippings, press releases, notes) (Box 6)
- Additional Material, Accession 1991-M-011
  - Leaflets, articles, clippings, and miscellaneous papers, 1939 Apr, 1940 August-Nov, undated (Box 1)